<dashboard script="setup.js,table_icons_inline_config_check.js" 
           stylesheet="setup.css,table_decorations.css">
    <label>Documentation</label>
      <row>
    	<panel>
	        <html>
	                <input id="_key" type="hidden"></input>
	
					<div>
	                    <h3>1. Import web server log data</h3>
	                    <p class="" id="1-loading">The Splunk App for Web Analytics currently supports data from Apache and IIS logs. Make sure you use the sourcetype access_common, access_combined or iis for this data. If you already have data in Splunk under a different sourcetype you can use <a href="../../manager/launcher/data/props/sourcetype-rename?ns=SplunkAppForWebAnalytics&amp;pwnr=-&amp;search=&amp;app_only=1" target="_blank">sourcetype renaming</a> or by modifying the <a href="../../manager/launcher/saved/eventtypes?ns=SplunkAppForWebAnalytics&amp;sort_dir=desc&amp;search=web-traffic&amp;sort_key=name&amp;app_only=True" target="_blank">eventtype web-traffic</a> to include the names of your sourcetypes.</p>
	                	<p>The app comes with two sets of sample data for Apache and IIS. You can enable these static sample inputs by going into <a href="../../manager/SplunkAppForWebAnalytics/data/inputs/monitor" target="_blank">Settings->Data inputs->Files &amp; Directories</a></p>
	               		<p>If your data is stored in an index that is not searched by default for your Splunk user, you need to add All non-internal indexes (or the specific index in question) to the Selected indexes in <a href="../../manager/SplunkAppForWebAnalytics/authorization/roles" target="_blank">Access controls -> Roles -> [ROLE NAME]</a></p>
	                </div>
	                
			</html>
			<table id="check_1" class="check">
				      <title>Web Server Log Data check (tag=web | head 5)</title>
				      <search>
				          <query>
				            tag=web | head 5 | stats count AS Events | eval Check=Events
				        </query>
				        <earliest>-1y@y</earliest>
				        <latest>now</latest>
				      </search>
			</table>   
	      	<html>         
	                <hr/>
	                
	                <div>
	                    <h3>2. Configure websites</h3>
	                    <p class="" id="2-loading">The Splunk App for Web Analytics works in a multi website environment. Websites are configured from a combination of the host and the source field. Each event with that unique combination will be tagged with the corresponding website name in the field "site". You can use wildcards (*) in the Source and Host field to select multiple files matching a pattern. There is a <a href="sites_setup?form.filter=*&amp;earliest=0&amp;latest=" target="_blank">website setup form page</a> that allows you to add these in an easy way. </p>
	                   <p>
	                   	Here are some examples of valid website configurations with or without wildcards
	                   	</p>
	                   	<p>
	                   		<h4>No wildcards</h4>
	                   	<table>
	                   		<tr>
	                   			<th>Site</th>
	                   			<th>Host</th>
	                   			<th>Source</th>
	                   		</tr>
	                   		<tr>
	                   			<td>roadrunner.com</td>
	                   			<td>server1</td>
	                   			<td>/var/log/httpd/access_log</td>
	                   		</tr>
	                   		<tr>
	                   			<td>roadrunner.com</td>
	                   			<td>server2</td>
	                   			<td>/var/log/httpd/access_log</td>
	                   		</tr>
	                   	</table>
	                  </p>
	                  <br />
	                  <p>
	                   <h4>With wildcards</h4>
	                   	<table>
	                   		<tr>
	                   			<th>Site</th>
	                   			<th>Host</th>
	                   			<th>Source</th>
	                   		</tr>
	                   		<tr>
	                   			<td>roadrunner.com</td>
	                   			<td>server*</td>
	                   			<td>/var/log/httpd/access_*</td>
	                   		</tr>
	                   	</table>
	                   </p>
	                   <br />
	                    <p>The data in the setup form will be stored in the lookup file called WA_settings.csv. You can also manually edit this file. The websites setup page can be found under <a href="sites_setup?form.filter=*&amp;earliest=0&amp;latest=" target="_blank">Setup->Websites</a>.</p>
	                </div>
	     	</html>
	     	<table id="check_2" class="check">
				      <title>Website Configuration check</title>
				      <search>
				          <query>
				            | tstats prestats=t count where index=* by host,source,sourcetype  | search [rest /services/properties/eventtypes/web-traffic/search | eval search=value] | stats count AS events by host, source  |  lookup WA_settings source AS source host AS host OUTPUTNEW value AS site | eval Check=site | fields host source Check	
				        </query>
				        <earliest>0</earliest>
				        <latest>now</latest>
				      </search>
			</table>
	      	<html>   
	                <hr/>
	                
	                <div>
	                    <h3>3. Run lookups</h3>
	                    <p class="" id="3-loading">Once the data has been imported run the two lookups <a href="report?s=%2FservicesNS%2Fnobody%2FSplunkAppForWebAnalytics%2Fsaved%2Fsearches%2FGenerate%2520user%2520sessions" target="_blank">"Generate user sessions"</a> and  <a href="report?s=%2FservicesNS%2Fnobody%2FSplunkAppForWebAnalytics%2Fsaved%2Fsearches%2FGenerate%2520pages" target="_blank">"Generate pages"</a>. These will be used throughout the app. Once run the first time, they will automatically be updated via two scheduled searches that runs every 10 minutes that adds any new data coming into the app. Running these lookup searches might take a long time depending on how much data you have in Splunk but its important you let the searches finish before you move on to the next step. If you have too much data to run these for everything you can modify the time period to something less than "All time" which is the default time period. The lookup reports can be found under Setup->Lookups or by using the links above. It's important that thes searches return results. If not, the app will not work.</p>
	                </div>
	    	</html>
	    	<table id="check_3" class="check">
				      <title>Lookup check</title>
				      <search>
				          <query>
				            | inputlookup WA_sessions | stats dc(http_session) AS Sessions | appendcols [| inputlookup WA_pages.csv | stats dc(http_request) AS Pages] | transpose | rename column AS Lookup "row 1" as Count | eval Check=Count
				        </query>
				      </search>
			</table>
			<html>   
	             <p class="">Please note that the Sessions lookup might return 0 if all sessions have already been copied over to the datamodel, the Sessions lookup will only keep data indexed in the last 4 hours. If the data model is accelerated and the acceleration is complete (or almost complete) having 0 in the Session lookup is alright. </p>
	    	</html>
	      	<html>         
	                <hr/>
	                
	                <div>
	                    <h3>4. Enable data model acceleration</h3>
	                    <p class="" id="4-loading">The Splunk App for Web Analytics uses data model acceleration extensively to power the dashboards. Once the lookups in the previous step has completed you should <a href="../../manager/SplunkAppForWebAnalytics/data_model_manager?app=SplunkAppForWebAnalytics" target="_blank">enable acceleration for the data model "Web"</a>. The data model can be found under <a href="../../manager/SplunkAppForWebAnalytics/data_model_manager?app=SplunkAppForWebAnalytics" target="_blank">Settings->Data models</a>. Set the summary range appropriately depending on how long you want to keep the data, > 1 Month. The data model is updated every 10 minutes in order for the sessions to get picked up properly. The data model acceleration needs to finish before you will see any data in any dashboard except the "Real-Time" dashboard which uses raw log data as source. That means that you initially might not see data until the data model has finished building. This could initially take up to an hour depending on how much data it is trying to build. </p>
	                </div>
	     	</html>
	     	<search ref="Data Model Acceleration Details" id="globalDMSearch"></search>
			<table id="check_4" class="check">
				      <title>Data Model Acceleration check</title>
				     <search>
						 <query>
						      <![CDATA[
| rest /servicesNS/-/-/data/models
| rename "acceleration.earliest_time" as Acceleration_Retention "eai:acl.app" as App "acceleration.cron_schedule" as Cron "acceleration" as Acceleration title AS Data_Model
| table Data_Model App Acceleration Cron Acceleration_Retention updated 
| eval Cron=if(isnull(Cron),"",Cron)
| join App type=outer [| rest /servicesNS/nobody/SplunkAppForWebAnalytics/admin/summarization/tstats:DM_SplunkAppForWebAnalytics_Web | fields eai:acl.app summary* 
| rename summary.access_count AS "Access_Count" 
summary.access_time AS "Last_Access"
summary.buckets AS "Buckets"
summary.complete AS "Status"
summary.size AS "Size_on_Disk_(Mb)"
summary.last_error AS "Last_Error"
summary.time_range AS "Summary_Range"
summary.mod_time AS "Updated"
summary.earliest_time AS "Min_Time"
summary.latest_time AS "Max_Time"
summary.is_inprogress AS "Summary_in_Progress"
eai:acl.app AS App
| eval Status=round(Status*100,2)."%"
]
| table Data_Model App Acceleration Acceleration_Retention Cron Summary_in_Progress Status Size_on_Disk_(Mb) Last_Error Min_Time Max_Time Now_Time Lag_Seconds Lag_Minutes Lag_Hours
| where like(Data_Model,"Web")
| eval Status=if(isnull(Status),"0.00%",Status)
| fields Acceleration Status | transpose | rename column AS Web "row 1" as Value | eval Check=Value
						]]>
						</query>
					</search>
			</table>
	      	<html>         
	                <hr/>
	          		
	                <div>
	                    <h3>5. Configure goals (Optional)</h3>
	                    <p class="" id="6-loading">If you want to monitor certain browsing paths or pageviews you can configure goals. This is used if you for instance want to get conversion rates or funnel abandonment rates. You can find the <a href="goals_setup?form.field1.earliest=%40y&amp;form.field1.latest=now&amp;form.startswith=&lt;No%20start&gt;&amp;earliest=0&amp;latest=" target="_blank">Goals setup page here.</a>   </p>
	                </div>
	      	</html>
	      	<html>        
	                  <hr/>
	                
	                 <div>
	                    <h2>Troubleshooting</h2>
	                    <h3>The lookup searches are not returning any data</h3>
	                    <p class="">In the context of the app, try and do the search for:</p>
	                    <blockquote>tag=web</blockquote>
	                    <p>If this <b>is not</b> returning any results I suspect you are not seeing the data because it is stored in a non-default index and the user in Splunk does not search in non-default indexes automatically. Another issue might be that you are not using any of the pre-configured sourcetypes. See Setup point 1 above.</p>
	                	<p>If this <b>is</b> returning results, double check that each entry has the "site" field populated. It's crucial that this field exists in your data. See Setup point 2 above. </p>
	                	
	                	<h3>All or some dashboards are returning "No results found"</h3>
	                	<p class="">As the app relies heavily on data model accelerations you will not see anything in any dashboards (except the "Real-Time" ones) until this acceleration has completed. Initially this could take a while. There is a <a href="data_model_audit" target="_blank">"Data Model Audit"</a> dashboard that will tell you if the acceleration is complete or not. </p>
	                	
	                </div>
	        </html>
        </panel>
    </row>
</dashboard>